# **Ashish Kumar**

## Frontend Developer

Solution-driven Fronted Developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS, React and JavaScript. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over 10 years with 8 years relevant, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations.

### Contact

#### **Address**

Delhi, India 110096

#### **Phone**

08826166899

#### E-mail

ashishyadav2758@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/as hishyadav2757/

#### **WWW**

https://github.com/jf-ashishyadav/

### **Technical Profile**

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- React
- Redux
- Adobe Photoshop
- Git / bidbucket
- Angular beginner

# Competencies

Project estimations

Code debugging

**UI** improvements

Requirements gathering

Usability understanding

# **Work History**

July 2021 - Current

# Front End Developer(React)

J&F INDIA PVT. LTD., NOIDA

- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Teamed on user-centric design strategy in translation of UX and business requirements into coded solutions.
- Improved tools to boost user interaction and deliver design versatility.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Experienced React developer with 2.5s years of expertise in IT solution provision. Focused on UI and React development for multifaceted product handling various modules, including user management, email management, and HR portal.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on prerelease software project development

Sep 2015 -June 2021

# **UI Developer**

J&F INDIA PVT. LTD., NOIDA

- Improved and expanded project platforms using JavaScript to develop rich User Interfaces.
- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Integrated UI features complying with prescribed code standards and technical design guidelines.
- Drove UI requirements through to implementation, complete with accurate sizing estimates and task breakdowns.
- Seasoned professional with 6 years of experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, and SaaS.
  Successfully delivered over 100 projects in ecommerce and medical domains, showcasing expertise in frontend development and UI design

**CSS** 

HTML

Front End Web Development

Web Design React

**UX** Design

Website optimization

Agile Workflow

Technical Analysis

# Languages

**ENGLISH** 

HINDI

#### AUG 2013 -SEP 2015

## **HTML Developer**

SPARX IT SOLUCTIONS NOIDA, NOIDA

- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, and JSON coding.
- Adhered to SEO best practices while designing sites.
- Web designer with 2.5 years of experience specializing in HTML, CSS, and jQuery. Proficient in creating visually appealing and responsive websites. Demonstrated expertise in user interface design, ensuring seamless user experiences across various platforms.

### Certifications

Full-Stack Web Developer

https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/ae89 9de804fe1fbfb5df9f976b982ad0cc80995018427b6c9b a0085444530ec7

### Webpack 4

https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/41dd 38891435993ef30108d3ca8b44bf30111435be3dc6009 ea0ee88881c3144

### HTML Essential Training

https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/9185c f42f9e102c9430262ceafbdf9bcf10beec817603d0fe01 bb8c9b436707c

### JavaScript Essential Training

https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/75583 8b8b744a3a67d3f6661812befca4df7741c45aa2238 bf3499a34214d2e

#### Git Essential Training

https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/2c1f9 c695ba88c93b416a59eb9561139cedbb1e7093d0713 8adb0d0b3d1709ec

### Education

2009-07 -2012-07

### **Bachelor of Arts**

CSJM University Kanpur - KANPUR